<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<!--    <b>жирный шрифт</b>-->
<!--    <i>наклонный шрифт</i>-->
<!--    <u>подчеркнутый шрифт</u>-->

<resources>
    <string-array name="level">
        <item>3x3</item>
        <item>4x4</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="type">
        <item>classic</item>
        <item>snake</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="text_angry_squirrel">
        <item>\"I\'m happy for you! (no).\"</item>
        <item>\"Well, so-so result.\"</item>
        <item>\"I expected more from you.\"</item>
        <item>\"And there was a lot of talk…\"</item>
        <item>\"It could have been better.\"</item>
        <item>\"Go train!\"</item>
        <item>\"Rush for the nuts, two-legged!\"</item>
        <item>\"Get out of here!\"</item>
        <item>\"You\'ll improve later, though, you won\'t.\"</item>
        <item>\"Train on cats!\"</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="facts_about_squirrel">
        <item>Fact 1.
\nSquirrels are a genus of rodents in the squirrel family.
\nSquirrels are found everywhere except Australia and Antarctica.
</item>
        <item>Fact 2.
\nThe genus of squirrels includes about 30 species distributed in Northern and
South America, Europe and the temperate zone of Asia.</item>
        <item>Fact 3.
\nTypes of squirrels differ in coat color, body structure, diet,
lifestyle and habits.</item>
        <item>Fact 4.
\nSquirrels come in different colors: black, red, brown, gray.</item>
        <item>Fact 5.
\nThe common squirrel, or \"veksha\", is the only representative of the genus of squirrels in
the fauna of Russia.</item>
        <item>Fact 6.
\nRaccoons, snakes and owls are considered the main enemies of these rodents.</item>
        <item>Fact 7.
\nFrom the name of the change coin \"Bela\" comes the modern name of the squirrel.</item>
        <item>Fact 8.
\nFossils of an ancient squirrel have been found in North America.</item>
        <item>Fact 9.
\nSquirrels love only shady and dry forests.</item>
        <item>Fact 10.
\nSquirrels have existed on our planet for about 50 million years.
During this time, no changes have occurred with them.</item>
        <item>Fact 11.
\nThe smallest species is considered to be the dwarf African squirrel.</item>
        <item>Fact 12.
\nThe animal likes to eat: in a week, the squirrel eats an amount of food equal to its weight.
And the weight of an adult reaches 2 kilograms.</item>
        <item>Fact 13.
\nThe squirrel is a champion in the diversity of the diet. Squirrels are omnivorous,
their diet includes about 150 seeds of different trees.
Its main part is coniferous seeds: spruce, pine, cedar, fir, larch.</item>
        <item>Fact 14.
\nIn oak forests, the squirrel will not disappear either – it will eat acorns and hazelnuts.
The protein menu also includes mushrooms, berries, herbs, mosses, lichens, tubers and rhizomes.
If the nut harvest was not good enough, squirrels feed on buds and
young shoots of trees.</item>
        <item>Fact 15.
\nSquirrels can also be predators. In addition to plant food,
they also like to eat insects, eggs and even small birds,
mammals and frogs.</item>
        <item>Fact 16.
\nBlack rodents are characterized by increased body temperature.</item>
        <item>Fact 17.
\nLike many rodents, the squirrel makes supplies for the winter – they hide nuts,
acorns, cones and mushrooms in tree hollows, and some species are buried in the ground.
But often the animal forgets where he hid his food.
In this case, the poor memory of squirrels is beneficial to the forest – nuts forgotten in the ground
germinate and replenish the forest with new trees.</item>
        <item>Fact 18.
\nSquirrels do not hibernate in winter, but in severe frosts they may
not leave the nest for several days. Despite the fact that the squirrel is a solitary animal,
during cold weather, the animals can gather in groups of three to six squirrels and
bask in one nest.</item>
        <item>Fact 19.
\nThe squirrel\'s nest is called \"gayno\", and one animal usually gets a lot,
up to 15 such dwellings. Most often, the nest is arranged in a hollow tree or in a birdhouse,
lining everything inside with dry leaves, stems, moss, feathers.
If there is no suitable hollow or birdhouse, the animals build their home between the branches of a tree,
at a height of 7-12 meters.</item>
        <item>Fact 20.
\nReproduction in squirrels occurs mainly twice a year — in winter and in summer.
During the mating period, males run after females, but the females choose their own mate.
The squirrel mates with one male once.</item>
    </string-array>
</resources>